ipswitchft.com 2019-03-30

# Privacy Policy - Ipswitch

Last updated September 5, 2018

Ipswitch respects the privacy of visitors to www.ipswitch.com, other Ipswitch Web sites and their related Web pages, product pages, URLs, blogs and communities (each a “Website” and collectively the “Websites”).  This Privacy Policy outlines the information We will collect and how We will use that information. Please read this web page carefully. If You are not comfortable with the policies and practices it describes, You should not use the Websites.  As noted below, We may change this privacy policy at any time in Our sole discretion.

As used herein, the words “User,” “You” and “Your” mean Users of the Website and the words “We,” “Our,” “Us” and “Ipswitch” mean Ipswitch, Inc., the owner and operator of the Website.

By using Our Websites, you agree to this Privacy Policy. This is Our entire and exclusive Privacy Policy and it supersedes any earlier version. We may change it by posting a new version on Our Website and by Your use of the Website after posting, You consent to the change.

Your information is being collected solely by Ipswitch.

### **Collection of personally identifiable information**

We will not collect any personally identifiable information about You unless You provide it to Us voluntarily and give Your express consent to use it.

We collect personally identifiable information for the purposes listed below. 

**Purchase:  **In addition to obtaining Your name and other personal information, which may include Your email address, postal address, and phone number, We may identify and log Your browser type when You purchase our software online.

**Contact and/or Billing Information:  **We may ask for Your contact or billing information when You place an order, download an evaluation, join a discussion list, subscribe to a newsletter, contact Us for support (technical or customer), or request related services requiring submission of contact and/or billing information.

**User Surveys:  **Your participation in surveys is optional, although We may require your participation as a condition to a trial use of Our software. We use this information to help Us improve Our software, plan marketing initiatives, develop new products and communicate with You about products, services or other topics that We think may interest You.

**Other Content:  **You may be required to provide personal information in order to access whitepapers, e-books, videos, demos or other forms of content.

**Shopping Cart:**  We use cookies to track the pages you visit, identify you as a previous visitor to our Web site and keep track of items in your shopping cart. We may tie the cookie to any personal information we have about you.

### **Use of personally identifiable information**

We may use the personal information You provide Us for a variety of purposes, including support, authentication, marketing, and may share information for sales and marketing with Our affiliates. We may also use Your personal information to inform You of special offers, upgrades and other Ipswitch products and services the products and/or services of other third parties that may be of interest to You.

### **Sharing of personally identifiable information**

We may share personally identifiable information with other persons in the circumstances listed below.

**For legal purposes:  **To protect Ipswitch and others, We may release personal information and IP addresses when We believe release is appropriate to comply with the law or with legal process (such as a warrant, subpoena, or other court order); to enforce Our software licenses, service agreements, Terms of Use and other rights; or to protect the rights and safety of others. This may include exchanging information with law enforcement agencies, or with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

**To persons who help Us provide Our products and services to You:  **We may provide personal and other information to third parties who work for Us, such as companies that verify credit card information, process credit card payments, fulfill orders, provide customer service, analyze customer data, remove repetitive information from customer lists, and provide marketing services. Any such company or third party is required to maintain the confidentiality of that information and is prohibited from using that information for any purpose other than as authorized by Us.

**As part of a sale of Our assets or a merger of Our company:  **We may in the future sell all or part of Our assets or be involved in a merger. It is customary for User information to be included with the transferred assets in these types of transactions.  However, We will take steps to assure that any personal information is used in a manner consistent with the terms under which it was collected.

**To the Bureau of Export Administration:  **We are required by law to furnish a report to the United States Bureau of Export Administration stating the names and addresses of all non-U.S. businesses or organizations (but not individual consumers) who purchase online or register any of Our software that contains an encryption feature.

### **European Union Residents**

Ipswitch complies with EU Directive 95/46/EC, EU General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States.

If you are located in the European Union, any personally identifiable information you provide us will also be governed by our standard Data Protection Addendum. To obtain a copy of the Data Protection Addendum, please contact us via email at: privacy@ipswitch.com.

### **Collection and use of non-personally identifiable information**

We may also collect information about You that is not personally identifiable. Non-personally identifiable information that Ipswitch collects is limited to the below scenarios:

**Cookies:** Ipswitch uses cookies on its own behalf to track the use and navigation on the Websites to better tailor the site for You when You return. Ipswitch uses a third party vendor to help measure and analyze the effectiveness of its Websites and how visitors use its Websites. Cookies are identifiers that a web site can send to Your browser to keep on Your computer to facilitate Your next visit. When You visit Our Websites, Our server logs Your IP address, the time and duration of Your visit, which pages You view. You will be notified of the use of cookies the first time You access the Websites on a different device. If You access our Websites from a member country of the European Union, Ipswitch will not install cookies before obtaining Your explicit consent and if You chose to refuse some or all cookies, some areas and features of the Websites may not function properly and/or You may not be able to access some parts of the Websites. Information may include the following:

**Web Beacon for Email Communication:** A web beacon is a small image We place in Our Web-based e-mail communications. Web beacons allow Us to access Our cookies to tell Us whether You have viewed our e-mail. If You chose to not accept the cookies on our Websites, the web beacon will provide Us only with information that an email has been viewed, but We will not be able to identify the visit with Your browser.

**Product Usage:** Some of Our products may transmit system, device, or other product usage related information back to Us. Depending on the application/product, this information may be anonymous or it may be associated with You.

**Support Exchanges:** In some scenarios, system and non-personally identifiable information may be needed/requested in order to assist in a support exchange. This information is only collected when needed, and retained only for the duration necessary.

Ipswitch may also use third party services (such as Google Analytics, LinkedIn, Facebook) to perform services on its behalf, in particular to:

  * Analyze your browsing habits
  * Measure site audience
  * Analyze your interests
  * Offer targeted marketing or advertising
  * Allow You to share content from the services with other people on social networks or let other people know what You are looking at or what You think (e.g. the “Like” or “Share” button on Facebook)

Social Media features are either hosted by the company providing it or hosted directly on Our Website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the Privacy Policy of the company providing it. For more information on how these tools collect and use Your information, please refer to their respective Privacy Policies. By using Our Websites, You consent to the processing of data by these third parties in accordance with their privacy policies. To obtain a list of third parties We use to track cookies, please email [privacy@ipswitch.com](mailto:privacy@ipswitch.com).

### **Storage and Retention of Information**

Ipswitch retains non-personally identifiable information collected from Website visitors indefinitely. We retain personally identifiable information collected from You only as long as necessary for the purpose for which You provide it or as required by law.  We may maintain and process such information directly or indirectly in one or more databases in the United States or elsewhere.

**E-mails :** To unsubscribe from Ipswitch emails, [click here](http://info.ipswitch.com/UnsubscribePage.html).

If You opt out or unsubscribe, We may, in compliance with the United States CAN SPAM Act of 2003, run Our suppression list (addresses not to be emailed) against another list of names for an Ipswitch mailing or provide Our suppression list to a third party for such verification.

When You opt-out or unsubscribe, You are doing so from our marketing messages. We may continue to send You transactional messages relevant to our business relationship. Transactional messages include information on product updates and upgrades, Service Agreement and subscription expirations and renewals, responses to inquiries, surveys and other information related to the product You downloaded or purchased.

### **Measures in place to protect Your information**

We have implemented generally accepted security standards to protect information from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. Only Our employees and independent contractors have access to the information We collect, and these employees and independent contractors are made aware of and required to comply with Our privacy policy.

Our order process is encrypted using an Extended Validation (EV) SSL (Secure Socket Layer) certificate.

### **Other Sites or Third Parties**

This Website contains links to other sites maintained by third parties; We are not responsible for the privacy practices of, content from, or actions of such third parties. When You click on such a link, You will leave the Website. The privacy policy of the external Web site will then be in effect. These links to other sites do not imply affiliation or endorsement of any linked site in any way.

### **Public Forums**

We provide a Community to Our Users. Please note the following:

Use the Community at Your own risk. Ipswitch reserves the right to, at Our sole discretion and without notice, remove or refuse content.

Any information You post in the community becomes public information with the exception of support cases and license tags.

Your personal information displayed is limited (Your name when posting or commenting) and this visibility can be changed within the My Settings area of Your profile.

You can subscribe/unsubscribe to email notifications from the Ipswitch Community under the My Settings area of Your profile.

Posting any unsolicited commercial messages, spam, or any content not associated to the Ipswitch community is prohibited.

Posting any information that violates or infringes on any copyright, intellectual property, privacy or publicity rights, or violates any confidentially agreements is prohibited.

### **Children**

The Website is not directed at persons under 18 years of age and Our content and other services are not written, intended, or designed for persons under 18 years of age. We do not intend to collect any personally identifiable information from such individuals. Where appropriate, Ipswitch will specifically instruct children not to submit such information on the Website. If a child has provided Us with personally identifiable information, a parent or guardian of that child should contact Us at the mailing address or e-mail address listed at the bottom of this policy to have this information deleted from Our records. We will use reasonable efforts to delete the child's information from Our existing files.

### **Legal**

Ipswitch corporate Websites operate as-is and as available. Any warranties of accuracy, quality, title, fitness or merchantability are disclaimed. We are not liable for direct, indirect, incidental or consequential damages, or for events beyond Our direct control.

Massachusetts law governs this Policy, excluding conflicts of law principles. Any provision of this Policy that is illegal or unenforceable shall be deemed automatically conformed to the minimum requirements of law. Any legal actions against us must be commenced in Suffolk County, Massachusetts within one year after the claim arose, or be barred.

### **Exercising Your Rights**

All requests will be responded to within 30 days of inquiry. In some cases, We may not be able to remove Your personal information, as defined in applicable laws and regulations, in this case We will let You know if We are unable to do so and why. Depending on the scope of the request, Ipswitch reserves the right to charge a reasonable fee to cover any out-of-pocket costs incurred in connection with such a request.

To review the information We have collected or request corrections to Your data, please contact Ipswitch Customer Service at [customervalueteam@ipswitch.com](mailto:customervalueteam@ipswitch.com)

To unsubscribe from Our Marketing emails, [click here](http://info.ipswitch.com/UnsubscribePage.html).

To request the erasure of Your data, please contact [privacy@ipswitch.com](mailto:privacy@ipswitch.com)

Ipswitch welcomes Your feedback on Our privacy standards. If for some reason, You do not believe We are adhering to the standards set forth in this Privacy Policy, or for additional information, please contact [privacy@ipswitch.com](mailto:privacy@ipswitch.com).

Ipswitch’s headquarters are located at 15 Wayside Road 4th Floor, Burlington, MA 01803 USA. We can be reached by phone at 800-793-4825.
